# **MARC MARQUEZ**

### **FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER**

# **SUMMARY**

Detail driven Full Stack Web Developer with a passion for designing and delivering engaging and intuitive user-focused solutions. Possesses a unique knowledge base of refined industry experience, multi-platform cloud infrastructure expertise, and extensive team and timeline oriented product delivery methodologies.

- marc.marquez@gmail.com
- (916) 715-0972
  - in linkedin.com/in/marc-marquez

# **PROJECT WORK**

### **BUG/FEATURE TRACKER -** Code Institute Project / December 2018



Web/mobile responsive Django application using HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, and Bootstrap for frontend and Python, MySQL for the back-end. Python code implements account authentication, upvoting, and integrates with Stripe payments API to let users donate money.

# **DATA DRIVEN VISUALIZATION -** Code Institute Project / August 2018



Web/mobile responsive Flask application presenting data in charts and histograms using HTML5, CSS5, DC.js, D3.js and Crossfilter.js on the UI and Python with MongoDB on the back-end.

### **ROSEHIP PRODUCTIONS -** Code Institute Project / March 2018





Web/mobile responsive Angular application promoting an events coordination company using HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, and Bootstrap.

# **EXPERIENCE**

**LEAD ENGINEER -** Hewlett-Packard Enterprise, Roseville, CA / 2015 – 2017 Perform as the lead engineer to develop integration, system, and acceptance test framework automation scripts to execute in a large cloud infrastructure environment.

- Optimized automated test script execution that reduced downtime by 34% by developing and implementing a best practice strategy that streamlined test cases and test run sequences.
- Reduced commitment of engineering resources by 90% per release by consolidating ten test configurations into one large complex configuration and managed by one engineer.

### **SUBJECT MATTER EXPERT (SME)** / 2011 – 2017

Perform as the technical Subject Matter Expert (SME) on the development and sustainment of a web application for field and sales engineers. Collaborated with stakeholders to continually improve user experience and deliver updates efficiently.

- Led UI/UX redesign of original web application by working with the dev team to gather requirements, create user stories, and build prototypes/wireframes.
- Minimized engineering resources from 6000 hours to 600 hours in one year by leading the development and implementation of a feature that performed automated updates to database records using a user interface.

### **SYSTEMS TEST ENGINEER** / 2005 – 2015

Serve as a key member of a systems integration team to build and test multi-platform configurations using various system architectures, servers, operating systems, host bus adapters, network and storage devices.

Discovered, diagnosed and drove to resolution multiple hardware and software defects by utilizing Root Cause Analysis (RCA) techniques to describe, monitor, and update issues by gathering support data such as OS, kernel, and trace logs, and validating fixes.

# **EDUCATION**

### **BS / COMPUTER SCIENCE**

**CSU Sacramento** Sacramento, CA

# **DIPLOMA / FULL STACK SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT**

Code Institute Dublin, Ireland

# **SKILLS**

#### **LANGUAGES**

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Python

#### **LIBRARIES**

jQuery, Crossfilter, DC, D3

#### **FRAMEWORKS**

Django, AngularJS, Flask

#### **DATABASES**

SQL, MySQL, MongoDB

# **PAYMENT PLATFORMS**

Stripe, PayPal

### **VERSION CONTROL**

Git/Github

### **BUG TRACKING**

Bugzilla

### **OTHER TECHNICAL**

Bootstrap, Heroku, Wireframing, Debugging

### **GRAPHICS**

Photoshop, Gimp

### **SOFT SKILLS**

Leadership, Collaboration, Communication, Problem Solving, Creativity